Guide to Josephine Allen papers, ca.1977-2000
Allen, Josephine papers, ca.1977-2000
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Josephine Allen papers, ca.1977-2000
23-26-3197
Josephine Aona V. Allen
1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, course material, papers, organizational materials, CD.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Biographical and course material, proposals, papers, abstracts and correspondence of the career of Josephine Allen, including her involvement in the National Association of Social Workers.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Josephine Allen was Professor of Policy Analysis and Management (formerly the Department of Human Service Studies), Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Biographical and course material, proposals, papers, abstracts and correspondence of the career of Josephine Allen, including her involvement in the National Association of Social Workers.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Allen, Josephine Aona V.; Allen, Josephine Aona V.; New York State College of Human Ecology--Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management; New York State College of Human Ecology--Dept. of Human Service Studies.; National Association of Social Workers.
Subjects:
Social work education.; Social work with African Americans.
Places:
United States--Social policy.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Information/Activities
Box 1- Folders: 1-8
Series II. Correspondence
Boxes 1, Folders 10-13
Series III. Courses
Boxes 1, Folders 14-24
Series IV. Proposals, Papers and Abstracts
Boxes 1, Folders 25-45
Series V. Professional Organizations and Programs
Boxes 1, Folders 46-51
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Information/Activities
  - Academic Goals (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Activities participated in, 1980's (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles written by Josephine Allen (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Encyclopedia of Social Work entry, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Review, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1979-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Conferences (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Natural Resource Management and Sustainable Agriculture Program - Ghana, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Empowerment, Gender and Social Change in Africa & the African Diaspora, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Conferences: Social Trends and Outlook (1982); State of Black America (1984); Psychosocial Intervention Research: Social Work's Contribution (1996) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Retirement Party 2008, CD-#749 (Box 1, Folder 9A)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Prior to 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series III. Courses
  - HSS-475-Social Policy, 1986-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - HSS-475-Social Policy, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - HSS-370-Social Welfare as a Social Institution, 1988-1989 and 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - HSS-370-Social Welfare as a Social Institution, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - HSS-370-Social Welfare as a Social Institution, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - HSS-402-Supervised Study in Jamaica, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - HSS-474-Program Development in Social Services, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - HSS-400/600-Empowerment in Human Services, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - HSS-660-Public Policy and Program Planning, 1980-1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - HSS 660-Public Policy and Program Planning, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - HSS-675-Organization and Structure for the Delivery of Social Services and HSS-417-The Politics of Power in the Human Services, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series IV. Proposals, Papers and Abstracts
  - Life Experiences of Women in Rural Communities - interviews, 1980s (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Project Rural ROAD (Reach Out: AIDS/HIV/STD Discussion)- BLCC, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - The Life Experiences of Women Who Head Households, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Rural Women and Poverty, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Use of Media Technology in Social Work Practice, video "Our House", 1983 and 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Women's Development Fund Application- to travel to Kenya, 1983 and 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Women Who Head Households, 1983 and 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Proposal for a Department of HSS Instructional Development Project and Cornell Public Policy Institute (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Abstracts: Acceptance of Rural Community Residences for Mentally Disabled Adults Fostering a Relationship Between Formal and Informal Systems Perspectives on Racism in Field Settings Public Hearing: The Feminization of Poverty, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Abstracts: Acceptance of Rural Community Residences for Mentally Disabled Adults, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Fostering a Relationship Between Formal and Informal Systems, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Perspectives on Racism in Field Settings, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Public Hearing: The Feminization of Poverty, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Accessing Social Competence and Identifying Essential Community-Based Services for the Vulnerable Elderly, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ageism and Racism: Two Issues In Social Work Education and Practice, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Black America: Reflections on Survival in the Context of Social and Economic Retrenchment and The Impact of Current Social Policies on the Well-Being of America's Black Elderly (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Black Women in America (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Destigmatizing Mental Illness (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Doing More with Less: Lessons to be Learned from the Black Elderly, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Group Home Development and Neighborhood Acceptance of the Mentally Ill (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Housing and the Black Aged (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Perpetuating the Illusion of Power in the Human Services (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Public Attitudes About Mental Illness Near the Canadian Border and Public Attitudes About Illness: A Review of the Literature (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Racism in Field Settings: Perspectives of Students and Field Instructors (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The Roles and Status of Professional Women in Jamaica (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Strategies for Impacting on Public Policy Formation, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Women as a Major Force in the Planning and Implementation of Social Development Strategies (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Series V. Professional Organizations and Programs
  - NASW (National Association of Social Workers) correspondence when Josephine was the President, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - SSHARPP (Sisters for Higher Achievement while Reflecting a Positive Perspective), 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Faculty Development Program - 3rd BPD-IASWR-NIMH- final report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Faculty Development Program - BPD-NIMH-IASWR, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Faculty in Residence Program (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Teaching Assistants in HSS (Box 1, Folder 51)